[Music]
hello and thank you I'm Andre Pano and I
will be doing demos for you today in
this release we continue our investment
into warehouse in Inventory management
and we also added
num of features some were added by
internal R&D team but we also received a
lot of valuable contributions from the
community you can find all the details
in the release notes it also contains
screenshots but in this session I will
focus on one or actually number of
scenarios around
reservation and we will try to find
answers on questions how you as a user
can find the answer what is the status
of existing demand document where demand
document can be sales order or
production consumption or assembly order
or jobs and and so on and once you
figured out that this document is ready
for shipment or for consumption how to
move it to the next stage and start
processing maybe even in automatic mode
without your uh involvement and because
these two will be very much dependent on
the reservation status then the next
question or how do how to do
reservations in the most efficient way
let's
see let's start with exploring how would
you do this in the classical way so for
example you create sales
order and we click new and pick our
favorite
customer which will be of
course AUM Corporation and some item I
created special items to demonstrate
that this is a oalt way of doing things
all right right let's pick some quantity
the next field which is important to
populate for processing will be uh date
so it will be either requested delivery
date if your customer knows when they
want things to be available for example
if it's part of the bigger project like
construction or building something huge
and they need stuff in the delivered in
specific time or they don't care but
they would like to ask like as soon as
possible and in this case you can use
our already available order promising
functionality for example let's choose a
capable to promise and let's system to
calculate when things will be available
if we will place order right now okay in
couple of weeks accept and now the only
thing is to wait yeah wait till date uh
comes and then you need to check if
customer calls you and ask like what is
the status then you need to find the
document and in some situation you can
explore the reservation
okay there is no hope this request is
still in form of requisition line so
nobody actually submitted to to order uh
to vendor not good uh too many clicks
especially if there are so many so many
lines so what can we do better first of
all the good indicator that something
can be really shipped or used if it is
already available in in stock in
warehous so why not to check it and if
you have things already reserved then we
added a new field which shows reserved
from stock in a very simple way it has
three options none nothing is reserved
from stock partial if some quantity is
reserved from stock others are either
not reserved at all or are reserved from
a different source for example from uh
production output and they still need to
be produced or fully if this is also an
option if everything is available
reserved and it means you can just go
and do so this is per line if you have
multiple lines probably you would like
to understand the overall uh situation
in this case we added this control also
in the statistic pages of the different
documents we will take a look at it in
details later so Reserve from stock
relating to the whole document like okay
in this specific document nothing to to
be shipped because nothing is
available Okay so in some replenishment
mechanism reservation created
automatically what it is assembly to
order which are automatically reserved
capable to promise which creates a
supply linked to this demand and
reserved for it also you can do it if
planning mechanism is order or in some
cases you can activate reservation like
manually but but what if you're using a
lot for lot planning policy or if you uh
prefer to deal with a reorder Point
replenishment mechanism then you need
then reservation is not there you need
to reserve manually and this might be a
not that easy task not anymore with a
new page which is called reservation
worksheet you can do it in dramatically
less number of clicks let's start by
choosing get demand action and in this
request page we will ignore it for now
and press okay and what do we see here
we see that system actually gather
different demand it can be sales
transfer job assembly production
orders and all of them need to be uh
reserved but also they have items which
are both available on stock and not
reserved for something else so like okay
this is a good situation let me change
sorting and let's start
processing how do we do that we put
seven here then we h no of course not we
are not doing it one by one we have
probably couple of actions to automate
this process let's me press allocate
button and what happened magic yeah so
multiple lines where we received
recommended quantity to Reserve System
decided to do it in a safe way you can
see that uh you can see for example for
this line
we have a lot available and we have very
limited demand so like 100% can be
covered yeah in this case system
allocate stuff it also does it full
allocation if a quantity is enough even
if there are multiple
demands but what if quantity is not
enough for one or if it doesn't know how
to allocate available quantity among
different supplies is
Skip but let's go and take a look in the
allocation policies basically it's not
only option like this is a basic one
which is run by default and it executes
the safest allocation you can also add
additional one which is in this case is
equally and uh guess what it equally
distributes things you can combine
multiple stuff today it's only two we
plan to add more you can also add more
allocation rules which better fit your
company processes and
rules all right let's run it again and
we can see that now all 10 allocated
even if we needed 12 and here for this
four demands we received 15 quantity
each for each line that looks equal
enough okay but before we move
forward and actually do reservation let
me show you batches in some companies
more than one person is doing allocation
and they have different preferences so
let's take a look at the bdch which is
not that simple it has additional
settings available for example you can
apply different filters and focus on
specific type of demand somebody prefers
to do allocation only for production
orders because they are responsible for
this area others sales orders or maybe
you don't want to system to suggest
reservation for some orders or some
demand in the uh future like okay you
have order with a due date in 12 months
maybe it's not uh good idea to reserve
it right now so you can put some uh
period like starting and end
date uh instructing which uh documents
should be included into the reservation
also you can focus on items we have a
cool filter capability which allows you
to filter not only by number but
basically by any field you can have in
the the item table including custom
Fields so the same mechanism we have in
the demand for cast today plus location
somebody responsible per specific
location also you can Define different
allocation policies and if and there
combin combinations for
bches okay let's select this
one and go home get demand and in this
case I will uh first of all I will show
you that uh filters are copied from the
bdch okay and I will activate allocate
after populate toggle which will do
clicking instead of me so I just need to
run the stuff and
uh my location my items are proposed and
you can see that system already
allocated as much as possible including
equal allocation of partially available
items
okay
we also use accept toggle when we deal
with
reservations so let's select these four
lines and mark them as also accepted
because we would like to apply this
change and click make reservation you
can also decide if you want to apply
reservation for specific document type I
will go continue with all all right
click okay everything is reserved that
was uh long story but very efficient way
in reality to reserve things from the
stock this is very important information
from the stock all right how can we use
this information right now of course
statistics is
updated we will take at it later but
let's start with something which was
part of the product for a long time but
now we can take a look at this uh report
again so we are interested in sales
lines on yellow
location and let's take a
preview probably makes sense to zoom a
little bit and scroll down okay so I
have my very special items which is
called reserved fully partially or not
reserved and you can see it is has a
different status how how it is available
how it is reserved and system shows the
information so if you are not using any
advanced uh function it you can use this
report to update quantity in order lines
like the same way as it was possible
before but now with reservation
available if you use more advanced
techniques for example you prefer to use
Warehouse shipments uh in this case we
added a special report which has two
purposes purpose number one it can use
filters for example let's pick full
option for Reserve from stock uh
uh filter
option what does it mean it will
create Warehouse shipment for yellow
locations but only include lines which
are completely reserved let's click okay
and let's go and explore created
Warehouse shipments okay I have two of
those and this one has fully reserved
item and the second also has fully
reserved item only even if we remember
that the spec the second order contained
three lines originally including
partially and not reserved item so this
is like option number one to automate so
you can push Warehouse receipts for
processing to Warehouse team directly so
no need to actually go and analyze each
sales document
individually uh the same
functionality kind of the same
functionality also available in the
basic Warehouse when when we talk about
inventory PS I will select inventory
pick Reserve from stock full and partial
partial and filter by location
yellow some might be curious how I'm
going to use and Warehouse receipts and
inventory pcks from the same location
this is also something which changes in
this version let me click
okay and inventory PS were created let's
open them and explore okay in this case
I have PS for jobs and this is a fully
reserved let's scroll to the next one
one this one is fully and partially
reserved and if I will go to original
Source
document for example to job card I can
check first of all uh
statistics yeah in general the document
is partially available because some
lines are fully some lines are partially
let's take a
look and some lines are not reserved at
all what about quantity yeah quantity
res reserved you can see looks
different
okay uh let's go back to to very basic
scenarios when you do not use Warehouse
handling for example for consumption
let's go to consumption Journal which is
part of manufacturing model and
calculate consumption and we can also
have the same filter here for example we
will focus on full reservation status
let's click okay and we will get
two lines if I will drill down to the
list of components in this specific
order you will see yeah we have three
components but only one accordingly to
its name is fully reserved all right we
can go also to the order and let me
demonstrate you my favorite feature from
a client added into this release show
details uh let's open the order and we
can also take a look at the statistics
here again Reserve from St partial added
into multiple places so you can check
the reservation status basically on any
document so what we figured it out so
now you can check status of the demand
document uh based on its reservation
status much easier you just check the
statistic page but you don't need to do
it in reality because you can configure
your system to run some task into
background in the Via job queue and push
documents to the next stage for example
create Warehouse shipments or create
inventory pck or even to do uh update
quantity to to ship or quantity to
consume in documents and because both of
them are based on reservation we figure
it out how to use reservation worksheet
to do reservations in a very efficient
way as I mentioned during demonstration
I'm using yellow look location for
different kind of Warehouse handling if
you want to know more take a look at
what's new in warehouse management and
if you're already interested in
Warehouse handling it makes sense to
check another session where we
demonstrating new barcode scanning
capabilities on mobile
device also I would like to mention
different resources and let's start by
submit your idea even if it looks like
one directional because it has one
directional Arrow vot placed there and
ideas really matters we have a more
chatty conversation in a different for
it's called
Yammer the the first link on the on the
left please also join and then you can
participate in the design decisions uh
discussions and uh impact on what and
how is implemented for the product and
get also early information up front uh
many resources the all
valuable links are links available here
if you use this link BC
all thank you and let's stay in
touch